# Gustavo Penha

guzpenha10@gmail.com

### about

27 years Delft, NL

#### links

webpage twitter github google scholar

## languages

portuguese english

#### soft skills

time management communication learn and adapt

## research

I am a researcher in the field of computer science. My focus is on neural ranking models for conversational search & recommendation. I like to do research driven by curiosity, and I believe one of my strengths is time management and prioritization.

# selected publications

2021	On the Calibration and Uncertainty of Neural Learning to Rank Models for Conversational Search  EACL  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2020	Exploiting Performance Estimates for Augmenting Recommendation Ensembles RecSys Gustavo Penha, Rodrygo Santos
2020	What does BERT know about books, movies and music? Probing BERT for Conversational Recommendation  RecSys  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2020	Curriculum Learning Strategies for IR: An Empirical Study on Conversation Response Ranking ECIR Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2019	Introducing MANtIS: a novel Multi-Domain Information Seeking Dialogues Dataset  Gustavo Penha, Alexandru Balan, Claudia Hauff  Arxiv

# **experience**

2021-5–8	Worked on explanations for voice search on the Alexa team.	Amazon - US
2015–2018	Data Scientist Machine learning and data science projects.	Hekima - Brazil
2014–2015	Undergraduate Researcher Research on scientific collaboration networks.	UFMG - Brazil

# education

2019–now	Ph.D. Computer Science	TU Delft - Netherlands
2012–2018	B.Sc. and M.Sc. Computer Science	UFMG - Brazil